#### PROFRESSIONAL PROFILE

I'm an empathetic and curious technical and UX writer. I have an enthusiastic passion for leveraging technology to help people understand and solve problems through my writing.

My experience in the cloud software development, networking, and security industries has given me the technical know-how and perspective needed to produce clear, concise, and accurate documentation and UX writing deliverables as well as communicate and collaborate with software developers and product managers alike.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**



- Technical Writing
- Audience Analysis
- Project Planning 00000
- Content Strategy
- API Documentation
- Postman
- Wireshark
- git
- Markdown
- reStructuredText
  - 00000

- HTML/CSS/JS
- Python
- Java
- • Linux/Windows
- Software Troubleshooting
- WLAN controllers

- · Routing/Switching

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

- Empathy
- Collaborative (in-person & remote)
- Self-motivated
- Resourceful
- Thorough
- Written, verbal, and visual communication
- · Analytical and critical thinking
- Always learning and investigating
- Unafraid of asking questions or being

#### **PORTFOLIO & CONTACT**

- Portfolio: https://iwriteabout.tech
- **512-817-8069**
- https://github.com/holdenhewett
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/h0ld3nh3w3tt-08ab0b113/

# HOLDEN HEWETT

## TECHNICAL AND USER EXPERIENCE (UX) WRITER

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## AMAZON WEB SERVICES (AWS)

## Programmer Writer | Aug 2022 - Present

- Managed a months-long project related to improving internal continuous deployment (CD) processes that involved collaborating with SMEs across global teams, dealing with a high degree of ambiguity while still delivering results, and prioritizing writing tasks to align with the overall program's goals and deliverables during development.
- Decreased the time to install and setup Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) and enhanced security on corporate Windows devices by at least 50% as a result of drafting, validating, and writing a new setup procedure.
- Wrote a "reStructuredText quick reference" guide for doc contributors to quickly refer to for syntax and best practices instead of scouring the sprawling writing guide.
- Wrote custom linting rules for Vale using regex to allow contributors to see errors in their code before submitting for review.
- Created custom EditorConfig file to help reduce the amount of general formatting errors doc contributors make in code reviews so they don't have to change their dev environment configuration.

### ELEVEN SOFTWARE

## UX Writer & Customer Success Engineer | Feb 2019 - Aug 2022

- Researched, prototyped, and implemented API documentation suite to delight and improve developer understanding of Eleven's APIs.
- Obtained a Technical Writing Certification from Technical Writer HQ.
- Perform weekly bug and quality assurance testing on newly developed code and create thorough bug reports for developers and product managers.
- Developed support and UX content strategies to align with business goals.
- Created a comprehensive writing process to guide and focus writing tasks.
- Leveraged Google analytics and ZenDesk Explore to mitigate common support pain points through technical writing and documentation.
- Decreased year-over-year ticket count from 2019 to 2020 by 40% through support documentation, user guides, tutorial and training videos, and other deliverables.
- From 2019 to 2020, decreased weekly average ticket volumes by 50% through documentation and knowledge-centered support (KCS) practices.
- Increased tickets resolved (one-touch tickets) by 30% in 2020 through providing useful and relevant documentation.
- Integrated ZenDesk Guide custom theme code with GitHub for versioning and collaboration with internal developers.
- Created Python script to automate the manual process of calculating monthly support call SLA attainment.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### HORRY-GEORGETOWN TECHNICAL COLLEGE

#### A.A.S. Computer Networking - 2017

- Obtained CompTIA Network+ Certification.
- Built a fully functioning on-premises enterprise network, including Cisco switches, routers, and VoIP equipment.

## A.A.S. Computer Programming - 2017

- Built a medical appointment website with PHP, MySQL, and HTML, and CSS and built a SUSE Linux server to host it.
- Built a Java GUI client for the same medical appointment website.